markettools.com 2018-06-29

# Privacy Statement | MetrixLab

MetrixLab B.V. is concerned about privacy issues and wants you to be familiar with how we collect, use and disclose information that identifies you as an individual or relates to an identifiable person (“ **Personal Information** “).

By providing Personal Information to us, you agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you understand how we collect and use your Personal Information.

This Privacy Policy can be stored or printed using your browser’s print function.

## 1\. WHO IS THE CONTROLLER OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

MetrixLab B.V., located at Wilhelminakade 312, 3072 AR Rotterdam, the Netherlands is the company responsible (data controller) for the processing of Personal Information (“ **MetrixLab** “, “ **we** “).

## 2\. WHAT IS THE SCOPE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY?

This Privacy Policy describes our practices in connection with Personal Information that we collect through:

  * the website available at [www.metrixlab.com](https://www.metrixlab.com/), and other websites from which you are accessing this Privacy Policy (the “ **Website(s)** “);
  * Our social media pages (e.g., MetrixLab-hosted forums or communities) located at <https://www.facebook.com/metrixlab>; <https://twitter.com/metrixlab>;  [https://www.youtube.com/user/MetrixLab, ](https://www.youtube.com/user/MetrixLab)  <https://www.linkedin.com/company/metrixlab/> ,[ https://plus.google.com/u/0/107807185775128324763](https://plus.google.com/u/0/107807185775128324763), <https://www.instagram.com/metrixlab_global/>(collectively, our “ **Social Media Pages** “); and
  * HTML-formatted email messages and exit polls that we send to you and that link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “ **Services** “).

This Privacy Policy applies to all users of the Services.

## 3\. WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW?

We may collect your Personal Information when you:

  * _Contact us with your questions/comments/ideas/complaints:_ We may collect various information, depending on the manner in which you contact us (e.g., if you send us an email, we will collect your email address) and the reason for contacting us (e.g., if you have a complaint). In any case, we will collect your contact details so we can respond to your query.
  * _Subscribe to our newsletter mailing list:_ We will collect your first and last names and your email address if you wish to subscribe to our newsletter.
  * _When you report a problem with one of our Services:_ We will collect your first and last names and your contact details so we can respond to your report. You will also need to describe the problem that you have experienced with one of our Services so we can take care of it.
  * _When you visit the Websites:_ MetrixLab may also collect certain data from your computer and Internet connection, including the IP address of your computer, the date and time you accessed our Websites, the Internet address of websites from which you link to our Websites, the computer technology you are using (such as laptop or tablet) and your movements and preferences on our Websites. MetrixLab also uses cookies and similar technologies in compliance with our [Cookie Policy](https://www.metrixlab.com/cookie-declaration/).
  * _From other sources:_ We may receive your Personal Information from other sources, such as public databases; joint marketing partners; social media platforms; from your friends and contacts on social media platforms, as well as from other third parties.
  * _Offline:_ We may collect Personal Information from you offline, such as when you attend one of our events or call our customer service representatives.

If you submit any Personal Information relating to other people to us or to our service providers in connection with the Services, you represent that you have the authority to do so and permit us to use the information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## 4\. HOW MAY WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We may use Personal Information:

  * To respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests, such as to send you newsletters;
  * To send administrative information to you, for example, information regarding the Services and changes to our terms, conditions and policies;
  * To allow you to participate in prize draws, competitions and promotional activities and to administer these activities (some of these activities have additional rules, which could contain additional information about how we use and disclose your Personal Information, so we suggest that you read these rules carefully);
  * To facilitate social sharing functionality;
  * To allow you to send messages to friends through the Services (by using this functionality, you are telling us that you are entitled to use and provide us with your friends’ names and email addresses);
  * For our business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, fraud monitoring and prevention, developing new products, enhancing, improving and modifying our Services, identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and operating and expanding our business activities; and
  * As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal processes; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations and those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety and property, and that of our affiliates, you and others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies and limit the damages that we may sustain.

## 5\. WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION?

Your Personal Information may be disclosed:

  * To our _affiliates_ for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy;
  * To our third party service providers who provide services such as website hosting, data analysis, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, email delivery, auditing and other similar services;
  * To third-party sponsors of prize draws, competitions and other promotional activities;
  * To identify you to anyone to whom you send messages through the Services;
  * By you, on message boards, chat, profile pages and blogs and other services to which you are able to post information and materials (including, without limitation, our Social Media Pages) Please note that any information you post or disclose will become public information, and may be available to users of the Services and to the general public. We urge you to be very careful when deciding to disclose your Personal Information, or any other information, on the Services;
  * To your friends associated with your social media account, to other website users, as well as to your social media account provider, in connection with your social sharing activity, such as if you connect your social media account to your Services account or log into your Services account from your social media account By connecting your Services account and your social media account you authorize us to share information with your social media account provider and you understand that the use of the information we share will be governed by the social media site’s privacy policy. If you do not want your Personal Information shared with other users or with your social media account provider, please do not connect your social media account with your Services account and do not participate in social sharing on the Services;
  * To a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings); and
  * As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal processes; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations and those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety and property, and that of our affiliates, you and others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies and limit the damages that we may sustain.

## 6\. DO WE USE COOKIES?

We use cookies in accordance with our [Cookie Policy](https://www.metrixlab.com/cookie-declaration/).

## 7\. HOW ABOUT LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SERVICES?

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information and other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site or service to which the Services link. The inclusion of a link on the Services does not imply endorsement of the linked site or service by us or by our affiliates.

Please note that we are not responsible for the collection, usage and disclosure policies and practices (including the data security practices) of other organizations, such as Facebook, Twitter, Apple, Google, Microsoft, RIM or any other app developer, app provider, social media platform provider, operating system provider, wireless service provider or device manufacturer, including any Personal Information you disclose to other organizations through or in connection with the Apps or our Social Media Pages.

## 8\. HOW DO WE SECURE PERSONAL INFORMATION?

Your Personal Information is treated as strictly confidential and we have taken appropriate technical and organizational security measures against loss and unlawful processing of such information. This includes measures such as firewalls, data scrambling, SSL encryption (RC4 128 Bits), application proxies, monitoring technology and adaptive analysis of network traffic to trace any abuse of our network and its data contents. The Websites communicate with our database using the SSL-protocol, thus ensuring third parties are not able to read or edit any data.

Unfortunately, no data transmission or storage system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please notify us immediately about the problem by contacting us in accordance with the “How Can You Contact Us?” section below.

## 9\. WHAT RIGHTS DO YOU HAVE?

If you would like to review, correct, update, suppress or delete Personal Information that has been previously provided to us by you, you may contact us at: [info@metrixlab.com](mailto:info@metrixlab.com). As noted above, you can also log into your profile setting on the Websites and view, change or replace your own profile data.

In your request, please make clear what Personal Information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Information that you have provided to us suppressed from our database and, if applicable, let us know what limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Information that you have provided to us. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the Personal Information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes. There may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed.

If you are a resident of California, under 18 and a registered user of the Services, you may ask us to remove content or information that you have posted to the Services by contacting us at:  [info@metrixlab.com](mailto:info@metrixlab.com). Please note that your request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information, as, for example, some of your content may have been reposted by another user.

## 10\. WHAT ABOUT DIRECT MARKETING/ADVERTISING?

We do not use information from website registration to send direct marketing email, SMS or other messages about products and services. We also do not share our website identities or contact details with our clients for their direct marketing purposes.

We may contact you for the purpose of the recruitment process of the new panelists/prospects. For example, when you take part in people’s choice awards on one of our local ”Website of the Year Award” Websites, we may also offer you the opportunity to become our panelist during the voting process.

## 11\. HOW LONG DO WE RETAIN PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

## 12\. HOW OLD DO I HAVE TO BE TO MAKE USE OF THE SERVICES?

Our Services are not directed at individuals under the age of 18 (with the exception of the Netherlands where the minimum age is 16).

## 13\. WHERE DO WE TRANSFER PERSONAL INFORMATION?

Your Personal Information may be stored on a server located in Rotterdam (The Netherlands), but may also be processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers. By using the Services you consent to the transfer of your information to countries outside your country of residence, including the United States, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country.

## 14\. HOW DO WE HANDLE UPDATES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY?

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. Please take a look at the “LAST UPDATED” legend at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will publish these changes on our home page or send you an email with the changes to ensure you are always aware of which information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may publish this information.

## 15\. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US?

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at  [info@metrixlab.com](mailto:info@metrixlab.com)

Please note that email communications are not always secure; so please do not include any sensitive information in your emails to us.
